var readlineSync = require('readline-sync');

var chalk = require('chalk');

var optionsGreen = chalk.green;

var header = `
-----------------------------------------------
‚öΩ   ‚öΩ   ‚öΩ   ‚öΩ   üéæ   üéæ   üéæ   üéæ   üèè   üèè   üèè   üèè  
                                               
+++++++++üëã  WELCOME TO SPORTS QUIZ üëã ++++++++++
                                               
‚öΩ   ‚öΩ   ‚öΩ   ‚öΩ   üéæ   üéæ   üéæ   üéæ   üèè   üèè   üèè   üèè  
-----------------------------------------------
`;
console.log(chalk.red.bgWhite(header));

var questionUserName = 'May I know your name? ';

var userName = readlineSync.question(chalk.green(questionUserName + '\n'));


while(userName.length === 0) {
  console.log(chalk.redBright("Wait! you haven't entered your name!\n"));
  userName = readlineSync.question(chalk.green(questionUserName + '\n'));
}

var sportsList = [optionsGreen("Football ‚öΩ"), optionsGreen("Cricket üèè"), optionsGreen("Tennis üéæ")];

var greetingMessage = '\nWelcome to my quiz';

var score = 0;

userName = userName.charAt(0).toUpperCase() + userName.slice(1)

console.log((chalk.green(greetingMessage)) + ', '+ chalk.blue(userName) + ' üëã');

console.log(chalk.red('\nBefore playing the quiz, please go through the instructions'));

var instructions = `
---------------------------------------------------------------------- 
‚ú®   ‚ú®   ‚ú®   ‚ú®   ‚ú®    INSTRUCTIONS  ‚ú®   ‚ú®   ‚ú®   ‚ú®   ‚ú®   ‚ú®               
---------------------------------------------------------------------- 
1) There are two levels in this quiz. (Level-1 and Level-2)            
                                                                       
2) There 5 questions for each levels. In total, there are 10 questions.
                                                                       
3) If you qualify level-1 then you are eligible to play the level-2. ‚è´ 
                                                                       
4) You have to score atleast 3 points to qualify for level-2. ‚è´        
                                                                       
5) There are 3 topics that you have to choose from. You have to choose 
any one of them.                                                       
  a) Football ‚öΩ                                                        
  b) Cricket  üèè                                                        
  c) Tennis  üéæ                                                         
                                                                       
6) If you select the correct option of the question then one point will
be awarded. ‚úîÔ∏è                                                          
                                                                       
7) If you select the wrong option of the question then no points will  
be awarded. ‚ùå                                                          
                                                                       
8) If you try to skip the question, then no point will be awarded. ‚ùå   
                                                                       
9) Press '0' to stop the quiz üõë                                        
---------------------------------------------------------------------- 
`;

console.log(chalk.red.bgWhite(instructions));

var sportsChoice = readlineSync.keyInSelect(sportsList, chalk.red('Which sport do you like?')); 

if(sportsChoice === 0)
  console.log(chalk.red('\nGreat!, you chose ') + ' ' + sportsList[0]);
else if(sportsChoice === 1) 
  console.log(chalk.red('\nGreat!, you chose ') + ' ' + sportsList[1]);
else if(sportsChoice === 2) 
  console.log(chalk.red('\nGreat!, you chose ') + ' ' + sportsList[2]);
else 
  console.log(chalk.red('\nYou have stopped the quiz, See you later! üëãüëã'));

var questionSetFootballLevelOne = [
  {
    question: '1) Which of the following country won Football world Cup maximum times?',
    options: [optionsGreen("Germany"), optionsGreen("Italy"), optionsGreen("Argentina"), optionsGreen("Brazil")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Brazil")
  }, 
  {
    question: "2) Who got FIFA Best Player 2019 Award?",
    options: [optionsGreen("Neymar"), optionsGreen("L.Messi"), optionsGreen("C.Ronaldo"), optionsGreen("Luka Modric")],
    answer: optionsGreen("L.Messi")
  },
  {
    question: "3) When was the first official international football match was played?",
    options: [optionsGreen(1929), optionsGreen(1872), optionsGreen(1902), optionsGreen(1870)],
    answer: optionsGreen(1872)
  },
  {
    question: "4) How many countries played at the World Cup 2014 tournament?",
    options: [optionsGreen(36), optionsGreen(32), optionsGreen(28), optionsGreen(30)],
    answer: optionsGreen(32)
  },
  {
    question: "5) Which team was awarded the FIFA Fair Play Award at the World Cup 2018 tournament?",
    options: [optionsGreen("England"), optionsGreen("Spain"), optionsGreen("Japan"), optionsGreen("Croatia")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Spain")
  }
]

var questionSetFootballLevelTwo = [
  {
    question: "6) Which team scored the highest number of goals at the FIFA World Cup 2018?",
    options: [optionsGreen("Belgium"), optionsGreen("France"), optionsGreen("England"), optionsGreen("Croatia")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Belgium")
  },
  {
    question: "7) What color cards do the referees carry in a football match?",
    options: [optionsGreen("Red and Yellow"), optionsGreen("Black and White"), optionsGreen("Red and Green"), optionsGreen("Yellow and Orange")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Red and Yellow")
  },
  {
    question: "8) What is the usual length of time allowed for half-time interval in a football match? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("10 minutes"), optionsGreen("15 minutes"), optionsGreen("1 hour"), optionsGreen("25 minutes")],
    answer: optionsGreen("25 minutes")
  },
  {
    question: "9) Real Madrid plays football in which country? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Germany"), optionsGreen("Scotland"), optionsGreen("Spain"), optionsGreen("Italy")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Spain")
  },
  {
    question: "10) Which English football club has the nickname 'The Gunners'? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Chelsea"), optionsGreen("Arsenal"), optionsGreen("Aston Villa"), optionsGreen("Brighton")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Arsenal")
  }
]

var questionSetCricketLevelOne = [
  {
    question: "1) Which cricket team has won the most ICC Cricket World Cup titles? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("West Indies"), optionsGreen("India"), optionsGreen("England"), optionsGreen("Australia")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Australia")
  },
  {
    question: "2) Which of the following country did not won the ICC Cricket World Cup (50 over format) title so far? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Bangladesh"), optionsGreen("South Africa"), optionsGreen("New Zealand"), optionsGreen("All of the above")],
    answer: optionsGreen("All of the above")
  },
  {
    question: "3) When was first ICC cricket World Cup started?",
    options: [optionsGreen(1972), optionsGreen(1975), optionsGreen(1985), optionsGreen(1979)],
    answer: optionsGreen(1975)
  },
  {
    question: "4) Which Indian cricketer had won the ‚ÄúMan of the Match‚Äù award in the final of the ICC World Cup 1983?",
    options: [optionsGreen("Kapil Dev"), optionsGreen("Sunil Gavaskar"), optionsGreen("Ravi Shastri"), optionsGreen("Mohinder Amarnath")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Mohinder Amarnath")
  },
  {
    question: "5) Who was the captain of the Indian cricket team in the ICC World Cup 1983?",
    options: [optionsGreen("Sunil Gavaskar"), optionsGreen("Kirti Azad"), optionsGreen("Kapil Dev"), optionsGreen("None of these")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Kapil Dev")
  }
]

var questionSetCricketLevelTwo = [
  {
    question: "6) Which of the following country has hosted the ICC World Cup most times? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("England"), optionsGreen("India"), optionsGreen("Australia"), optionsGreen("West Indies")],
    answer: optionsGreen("England")
  },
  {
    question: "7) Which of the following is the oldest test cricket playing country in the world?",
    options: [optionsGreen("Australia"), optionsGreen("India"), optionsGreen("West Indies"), optionsGreen("South Africa")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Australia")
  },
  {
    question: "8) Where is the headquarter of the ICC? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("London"), optionsGreen("Cape Town"), optionsGreen("Sydney"), optionsGreen("Dubai")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Dubai")
  },
  {
    question: "9) When was ICC establised? ",
    options: [optionsGreen(1909), optionsGreen(1953), optionsGreen(1960), optionsGreen(1877)],
    answer: optionsGreen(1909)
  },
  {
    question: "10) Which of the following international competition is not organized by the ICC? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Champions Trophy"), optionsGreen("World Cricket League"), optionsGreen("Under 19 Cricket World Cup"), optionsGreen("Syed Mustaq Ali Trophy")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Syed Mustaq Ali Trophy")
  }
]

questionSetTennisLevelOne = [
  {
    question: "1) In which country tennis-originated ? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("USA"), optionsGreen("England"), optionsGreen("France"), optionsGreen("None of these")],
    answer: optionsGreen("England")
  },
  {
    question: "2) What is the length of Tennis-Court ? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("85-feet"), optionsGreen("78-feet"), optionsGreen("76-feet"), optionsGreen("110-feet")],
    answer: optionsGreen("78-feet")
  },
  {
    question: "3) Where is the headquarters of International Tennis Federation ? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Sydney"), optionsGreen("New York"), optionsGreen("London"), optionsGreen("None of these")],
    answer: optionsGreen("London")
  },
  {
    question: "4) Where did the Grand-slam, Australian-Open take place ? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Sydney"), optionsGreen("Brisbane"), optionsGreen("Canberra"), optionsGreen("Melbourne")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Melbourne")
  },
  {
    question: "5) Where did the Grand-slam, US-Open take place ? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("California"), optionsGreen("New Jersey"), optionsGreen("New York"), optionsGreen("Texas")],
    answer: optionsGreen("New York")
  }
]

questionSetTennisLevelTwo = [
  {
    question: "6) Which is the oldest-tennis-tournament in the world ?",
    options: [optionsGreen("Australia Open"), optionsGreen("US Open"), optionsGreen("Roland Garros"), optionsGreen("Wimbledon")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Wimbledon")
  },
  {
    question: "7) Which is the highest paying tennis tournament in the world ? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Australia Open"), optionsGreen("US Open"), optionsGreen("Roland Garros"), optionsGreen("Wimbledon")],
    answer: optionsGreen("US Open")
  },
  {
    question: "8) Roger Federer has won how many Grand Slams?",
    options: [optionsGreen(15), optionsGreen(17), optionsGreen(20), optionsGreen(19)],
    answer: optionsGreen(20)
  },
  {
    question: "9) Which of the following terms is used in the game of Lawn Tennis? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Deuce"), optionsGreen("Jockey"), optionsGreen("Punter"), optionsGreen("Scoop")],
    answer: optionsGreen("Deuce")
  },
  {
    question: "10) The famous Indian Express was a team of? ",
    options: [optionsGreen("Leander Paes and Mahesh Bhupati"), optionsGreen("Mahesh Bhupati and Rohan Boppana"), optionsGreen("Leander Paes and Yuki Bhambri"), optionsGreen("Yuki Bhambri and Rohan Boppana")], 
    answer: optionsGreen("Leander Paes and Mahesh Bhupati")
  }
]

var highestScoreFootball =[ 
  {
    name: 'Soumik',
    score: 8
  },
  {
    name: 'Anirudh',
    score: 7
  },
  {
    name: 'Samyak',
    score: 5
  },
  {
    name: 'Ayus',
    score: 3
  }
]
var highestScoreCricket = {
  name: 'Tanuj',
  score: 5
}

var highestScoreTennis = {
  name: 'Aniruddha',
  score: 5
}

function play(question, options, answer) {
  var index=readlineSync.keyInSelect(options, chalk.yellow(question));
  var userAnswer = options[index];
  if(userAnswer === answer) {
    score = score + 1;
    console.log(chalk.green("\nCorrect! ‚úîÔ∏è"));
    console.log(chalk.cyan("\nCorrect Answer: ") + answer);
    console.log(chalk.cyan("\nYour Answer: ") + userAnswer);
  } else if(userAnswer === undefined) {
    console.log(chalk.red('\nYou have skipped a question ‚ùå '));
  } else {
    console.log(chalk.red("\nWrong! ‚ùå"));
    console.log(chalk.cyan("\nCorrect Answer: ")+ answer);
    console.log(chalk.cyan("\nYour Answer: ") + userAnswer);
  }
}

function levelTwo(score, questions) {
  console.log(chalk.green('\n\nCongrats! you are eligible to play level 2 ‚è´'));
  for(var i=0;i<questions.length;i=i+1) {
    var currentQuestion = questions[i];
    play(currentQuestion.question, currentQuestion.options, currentQuestion.answer);
  }
}

function levelOne(questions) {
  for(var i=0;i<questions.length;i=i+1) {
    var currentQuestion = questions[i];
    play(currentQuestion.question, currentQuestion.options, currentQuestion.answer);
  }
}

if(sportsChoice == 0 || sportsChoice == 1 || sportsChoice == 2)
  console.log(chalk.yellow("\n\nLet's begin the quiz, All the best!! üíØ \t üíØ "));

if(sportsChoice === 0) {
  questions=questionSetFootballLevelOne
  levelOne(questions);
 if(score >= 3) {
    questions = questionSetFootballLevelTwo
    levelTwo(score, questions);
  } else {
    console.log(chalk.red('\n\nSorry! you are not eligible for level 2. üò¢'));
 }
} else if(sportsChoice === 1) {
   questions = questionSetCricketLevelOne
   levelOne(questions);
  if(score >= 3) {
    questions = questionSetCricketLevelTwo
    levelTwo(score, questions);
  } else {
    console.log(chalk.red('\n\nSorry! you are not eligible for level 2. üò¢'));
 }
} else if(sportsChoice === 2) {
   questions = questionSetTennisLevelOne
   levelOne(questions)
  if(score >= 3) {
    questions = questionSetTennisLevelTwo
    levelTwo(score, questions);
  } else {
    console.log(chalk.red('\n\nSorry! you are not eligible for level 2. üò¢ '));
 }
}

if(sportsChoice === 0 || sportsChoice === 1 || sportsChoice === 2)
  console.log(chalk.green("\nTotal Score is: ") + score);

if(sportsChoice === 0) {
  if(score > highestScoreFootball[0].score) {
    console.log(chalk.green('\n\nCongrats! You got the highest score üíØüíØ'));
  } else {
    console.log(chalk.red('Your score is less than the highest score üò¢, better luck next time! üíØ'));
  }
}

if(sportsChoice === 1) {
  if(score > highestScoreCricket.score) {
    console.log(chalk.green('\n\nCongrats! You got the highest score üíØüíØ'));

  } else {
    console.log(chalk.red('Your score is less than the highest score üò¢, better luck next time! üíØ'));
  }
}

if(sportsChoice === 2) {
  if(score > highestScoreTennis.score) {
    console.log(chalk.green('\n\nCongrats! You got the highest score üíØüíØ'));
  } else {
    console.log(chalk.red('Your score is less than the highest score üò¢, better luck next time! üíØ'));
  }
}

console.log(chalk.yellow('\n\nShare this quiz with your friends and also do share the final score'));
console.log(chalk.yellow('\nby tweeting or direct message to @soumik_72 on twitter.'));
console.log(chalk.yellow('\nI will add it in the leaderboard soon üíØ'));

var leaderBoard = `
--------------------------------------
üèÖ üèÖ üèÖ     LEADERBOARD   üèÖ üèÖ üèÖ         
--------------------------------------
`
console.log(chalk.red.bgWhite(leaderBoard));

var highestScoreBeaten = false;
var indexInsert=0;
for(var i=0;i<highestScoreFootball.length;i++){
  highestScoreBeaten=true;
  indexInsert=i;
  highestScoreFootball.splice(indexInsert, 0, {name: `${userName}`, score: `${score}`});
  break;
}

if(highestScoreBeaten) {
  for(var i=0; i<highestScoreFootball.length;i++) {
    console.log(chalk.red(highestScoreFootball[i].name) + ": " + chalk.yellow(highestScoreFootball[i].score));
  }
}


console.log(chalk.red.bgWhite('\n--------------------------------------'));

